Joel Rivera

Senior Front-End Engineer

407-994-8118 / joelrivera.me@gmail.com

Skills

React (Expert)



TypeScript (Expert)



Next.js (Expert)



Tailwindcss (Experienced)



AI-powered UI (Expert)



Web Accessibility (Skillful)



Links

My Website

GitHub

LinkedIn

Languages

English (Native)



Spanish (Native)



Professional summary

Senior Front-End Engineer boasting 10 years of experience, distinguished by a track record of building modern, AI-powered web applications. Having led initiatives to enhance code quality and web accessibility, this professional has also designed product demos securing significant revenue. Expertise in React, TypeScript, Tailwindcss, Next.js, and Web Accessibility ensures delivery of visually appealing, user-friendly interfaces.

Employment history

Development Lead, Endava

AUG 2021 - FEB 2024, REMOTE

- Led a high impact front-end unit testing initiative to define and establish testing best practices, and documentation. Increased code coverage from 0% to ~ 10% resulting in a higher quality and stable code base.
- Led an initiative to identify and rectify web accessibility vulnerabilities on the Endava website, and cultivated awareness by conducting an web accessibility 101 lunch and learn session focusing on awareness, importance, and practicality.

Senior Front-End Engineer, IBM

MAY 2015 - FEB 2021, NEW YORK CITY

- On the IBM DTE Solutions team, I designed and built flagship product demos for several Watson APIs like Watson Speech to Text, Watson NLU, and Watson Assistant, which helped IBM win over \$6 million in revenue from new client engagements.
- On the IBM Watson Prototypes team, I built Watson AI-powered user interfaces and interactive experiences for high profile clients like Starbucks, Geico, CNN, and Morgan Stanley.

Front-End Developer, Morgan Stanley

FEB 2014 - DEC 2014, NEW YORK CITY

- Developed user-friendly front-end interfaces using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to enhance the
 user experience and meet the business requirements of Morgan Stanley's financial services
 applications.
- Built internal microsites, published quarterly earnings reports, and maintained morganstanley.com in production.

Education

Self-Taught Education

FEB 2012 - PRESENT, REMOTE

I transitioned into a career in design and engineering through self-directed learning rather than a conventional Computer Science degree. My technical proficiency was honed through a combination of online educational platforms such as Pluralsight (formerly Code School), Codecademy, Treehouse, CSS Tricks, and MDN, along with practical experience gained from developing websites for local clients and engaging in personal side projects.

